<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on secML</title>
    <link>https://secml.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on secML</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://secml.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Seminar</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/starting-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/starting-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our first seminar meeting will be Friday, January 26 (not this Friday, which would normally be the first class day, since I will be getting back from California too late to meet this week). Meetings will be Fridays in Rice 032, 9:30am-noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;rsquo;re missing the normal first meeting, I want to do as much of the organizational stuff this week to be able to have a substantive first meeting next week. This means we will group students into teams, have a team assigned to lead the first class, and announced topic and readings by next Tuesday (Jan 23).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable this, everyone interested in participating in the class in any way should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Submit this form by Wednesday (Jan 24): &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/forms/FqSmUNHYBPbaKsg72&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/forms/FqSmUNHYBPbaKsg72&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the pcourse syllabus](/syllabus/), and follow the directions there to join the seminar slack group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will work out the teams based on the form submissions, and set up the schedule for leading classes/blogging. I will have office hours on Monday (Jan 22) at 2:30pm. People from the first presenting team will be expect to meet with me then (not necessarily everyone but at least some of the team), and anyone with questions about the seminar is also welcome to come by. (If this time works for the class, we&amp;rsquo;ll keep this as my regular office hours time for the semester.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry for missing the first class, but I think we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to manage most of what we would have done the first day electronically, and be able to have an effective first meeting on Jan 26.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus Posted</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/syllabusposted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/syllabusposted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/a&gt; is now posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This graduate-level special topics course will be offered in Spring
2018. Meetings will be &lt;strong&gt;Fridays, 9:30-noon&lt;/strong&gt; in Rice Hall 032. More
information will be posted here soon, but the seminar format will be
roughly similar to what we used to &lt;a
href=&#34;https://tlseminar.github.io&#34;&gt;TLSeminar&lt;/a&gt; last Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seminar will focus on understanding the risks adversaries pose to
machine learning systems, and how to design more robust machine
learning systems to mitigate those risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seminar is open to ambitious undergraduate students (with
instructor permission), and to graduate students interested in
research in adversarial machine learning, privacy-preserving machine
learning, fairness and transparency in machine learning, and other
related topics.  Previous background in machine learning and security
is beneficial, but not required so long as you are willing and able to
learn some foundational materials on your own.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; For more
information, contact &lt;A href=&#34;https://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans&#34;&gt;David
Evans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>