<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on secML</title>
    <link>https://secml.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on secML</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://secml.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 1: Intro to Adversarial Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/class1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/class1/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Background In supervised Machine Learning, we train models with training data along with the label associated with it. We extract features from each sample, and use an algorithm to train a model where the inputs are those features and the output is the label.
For classifying the testing data, the classifier uses decision boundary to separate points of the data belonging to each class. In a statistical-classification problem with two classes, a decision boundary partitions all the underlying vector space into two separate classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Week</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/first-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/first-week/</guid>
      <description>This message was also sent out by email.
Since not everyone has joined the slack yet, I&amp;rsquo;m sending this out by email, but please make sure to join https://secprivml.slack.com soon. I will use that for future communications.
I have grouped the 18 full participants in the class into three teams of six:
Team Bus:
Anant Kharkar
Ashley Gao
Atallah Hezbor
Joshua Holtzman
Mainuddin Ahmad Jonas
Weilin Xu
Team Gibbon:
Aditi Narvekar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Seminar</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/starting-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/starting-seminar/</guid>
      <description>Our first seminar meeting will be Friday, January 26 (not this Friday, which would normally be the first class day, since I will be getting back from California too late to meet this week). Meetings will be Fridays in Rice 032, 9:30am-noon.
Since we&amp;rsquo;re missing the normal first meeting, I want to do as much of the organizational stuff this week to be able to have a substantive first meeting next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus Posted</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/syllabusposted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/syllabusposted/</guid>
      <description>The Syllabus is now posted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>This graduate-level special topics course will be offered in Spring 2018. Meetings will be Fridays, 9:30-noon in Rice Hall 032. More information will be posted here soon, but the seminar format will be roughly similar to what we used to TLSeminar last Spring.
This seminar will focus on understanding the risks adversaries pose to machine learning systems, and how to design more robust machine learning systems to mitigate those risks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>