<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>secML</title>
    <link>https://secml.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on secML</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://secml.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 2: Privacy in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/class2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/class2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In today’s post we introduce some key concepts crucial to understanding the current state of privacy in machine learning. In a time where novel machine learning applications are seemingly announced weekly, privacy is becoming more relevant as learning algorithms play varied and sometimes critical roles in our lives. We introduce differential privacy and common ‘solutions’ that fail to protect individual privacy, explore membership inference attacks on blackbox machine learning models, and discuss a case study involving privacy in the field of pharmacogenetics, where machine learning models are used to guide patient treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;membership-inference-attacks&#34;&gt;Membership inference attacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reza Shokri, Marco Stronati, Congzheng Song, and Vitaly Shmatikov. &lt;em&gt;Membership Inference Attacks Against Machine Learning Models&lt;/em&gt;. IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (&amp;ldquo;Oakland&amp;rdquo;) 2017. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~shmat/shmat_oak17.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~shmat/shmat_oak17.pdf&#34;&gt;Shokri et al.&lt;/a&gt; attempt to attack black box machine learning models based on subtle data leaks based on the outputs. If the membership of a datapoint can be identified in the training set of a black box machine, it poses a significant privacy risk to the data of users of machine learning services. This is especially important for machine learning services such as Google Prediction and Amazon ML, as an inability to guarantee the privacy of training data would preclude a significant number of customers from using their services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack is based on the idea that there are noticeable patterns in outputs when the input is given to the model as training data. While no human would be able to pick up on a pattern of that nature, a machine learning model with a theoretically limitless data source has that power. As the purpose of machine learning is to notice and evaluate patterns beyond human recognition, using a machine learning model to attack black box machine learning models makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a machine learning model to attack the black box, it first needs to train against other models where it can verify its own accuracy. For this, similar models need to be created for evaluation. These models are called shadow models, and need to be trained on similar sample data to the original model. To generate training data, these models use hill climbing methods on the black box to seek high confidence areas. By then sampling data using a simple distribution about those points, somewhat accurate training sets can be created. Ideally, these sets will be roughly the same size and distribution of the target model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack model is then trained on a set of shadow models, using classifications based on whether or not the datapoint was in the training set of the shadow model. This theoretically works based on the attack model being able to locate areas in which the curves are overfitted in the shadow models and translate that into membership. Ultimately, the study produced results that ranged from 70% to 95% precision overall based on the target model. The model gave nearly no false negatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To limit the power of these attacks, more regularization can be used to minimize overfitting, as the overfitting patterns become less apparent as the curve fitting is minimized. However, differential privacy is the more general class of solutions that is the defining foundation of the current state of the field of privacy in machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;differential-privacy&#34;&gt;Differential privacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the explosion of data collection from various social platforms and the increasing usage of machine learning on personalized applications like personalized medication, medical diagnostics, genomics and face recognition, the collection of sensitive human data is inevitable. When dealing with personal information, it is paramount to preserve the privacy of any individual participating in the data set. In a word, it is necessary to ensure that an adversary does not learn about the presence or absence of any individual’s information from looking at the synopsis of the data set. This goal is the central motivation the concept of differential privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fully appreciate differential privacy, let us discuss some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lrdc.pitt.edu/schunn/cdi2009/presentations/Dwork.pdf&#34;&gt;alternative solutions&lt;/a&gt; to preserving individual privacy in a data set identify how each one fails in achieving the goal of privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;failed-alternatives&#34;&gt;Failed alternatives&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;1-allowing-only-group-queries&#34;&gt;1. Allowing only group queries&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems intuitive that individual data privacy can be preserved by restricting a user to only group queries. For example, a group query can be: “How many students in this class earned an A?”. But this blatantly violates the privacy if the user also queries “How many students in this class apart from Rick earned an A?”, where the end user can know if Rick received an A or not based on the answer to the two queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;2-add-random-noise-to-the-query-result&#34;&gt;2. Add random noise to the query result&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding random noise to the query result tends to obfuscate the relation between the input and the output, but an adversary can determine the noise distribution by repeated querying. Hence, this approach also fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;3-deterministic-perturbation-in-answering&#34;&gt;3. Deterministic perturbation in answering&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can deterministically map every output to another value in the vector space to obfuscate the input-output relation. But this becomes far too computationally complex in a high-dimensional regime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;4-withholding-sensitive-information&#34;&gt;4. Withholding sensitive information&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An easy, straightforward notion is to simply withhold any sensitive data before executing any query; however, this very action reveals information about the presence or absence of sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;5-make-output-independent-of-any-individual-record&#34;&gt;5. Make output independent of any individual record&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach certainly does not reveal the presence or absence of an individual in the data set. But this method is not of any practical use since, by mathematical induction, the output does not depend on the data set itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;6-k-anonymity&#34;&gt;6. K-anonymity&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to achieve obfuscation of a record is to group it with \(k\) other records for each attribute. Unfortunately, this method also fails in high-dimensional cases, where it has been shown to be feasible to still distinguish an individual record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;7-semantic-security&#34;&gt;7. Semantic Security&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semantic security is a strict notion in cryptography which ensures that the advantage of an adversary with an auxiliary information should be cryptographically small with or without the access to the output (ciphertext). In our query model, this definition is too strong and does not allow learning any useful information from the data set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;defining-differential-privacy&#34;&gt;Defining differential privacy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/NetflixPrivacy.pdf&#34;&gt;formal definition&lt;/a&gt; of differential privacy is given as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A randomized computation \(M\) satisfies \(\epsilon\)-differential privacy if for any adjacent data sets \(x\) and \(x’\), and any subset \(C\) of possible outcomes \(Range(M)\),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$Pr[M(x) \in C] \leq \exp(\epsilon) \times Pr[M(x&amp;rsquo;) \in C]$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, this means that the chance that an event occurs &lt;em&gt;with your data&lt;/em&gt; and the chance it would occur &lt;em&gt;without your data&lt;/em&gt; is closely bounded by a privacy budget \(\epsilon\). The figure below depicts the equation where the two lines denote the probability distribution over \(x\) and \(x’\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/secML/secML.github.io/master/src/content/images/img1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Response probability distribution&#34; /&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;(http://www.lrdc.pitt.edu/schunn/cdi2009/presentations/Dwork.pdf)&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Differential Privacy and Pan-Private Algorithms&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [6]
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another relaxed version of the above definition of differential privacy, called \((\epsilon,\delta)\)-differential privacy, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/NetflixPrivacy.pdf&#34;&gt;defined&lt;/a&gt; as below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A randomized computation \(M\) satisfies \((\epsilon,\delta)\)-differential privacy if for any adjacent data sets \(x\) and \(x’\), and any subset \(C\) of possible outcomes \(Range(M)\),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$Pr[M(x) \in C] \leq \exp(\epsilon) \times Pr[M(x&amp;rsquo;) \in C] + \delta$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above definition basically implies that with probability \((1-\delta)\), \(M\) preserves \(\epsilon\)-differential privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;properties-of-differential-privacy&#34;&gt;Properties of differential privacy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;: An \(\epsilon\)-differentially private algorithm can be extended to provide group privacy for a group size of \(k\) by scaling the privacy budget to \(k\epsilon\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Composition&lt;/strong&gt;: Composition of \(k \epsilon\)-differential privacy and \((\epsilon,\delta)\)-differential privacy methods leads to \(k \epsilon\)-differential privacy and \((k \epsilon, k \delta)\)-differential privacy methods respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;differential-privacy-with-laplace-noise&#34;&gt;Differential privacy with Laplace noise&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure \(\epsilon\)-differential privacy for a function \(f(x)\), we can add &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/NetflixPrivacy.pdf&#34;&gt;Laplace noise&lt;/a&gt; to it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$ f(x) + \text{Laplace}(0, \sigma)^d $$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where \(\Delta f = \text{max} || f(x)-f(x&amp;rsquo;) ||_1 \)  and \(\sigma \geq \frac{\Delta f}{\epsilon}\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us consider a working example. Consider that there are two adjacent data sets \(D\) and \(D&amp;rsquo;\) consisting of scores of students of a class, such that \(D\) and \(D’\) differ by only one student’s record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the function \(f\) that computes the class average. If, say, the minimum and maximum attainable scores are \(0\) and \(100\) respectively, then the sensitivity of \(f\) is \( \frac{100-0}{4} = 25\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, to release the class average of \(D\) is given by
\(\frac{65+83+77+56}{4}\) with \(\epsilon\)-differential privacy,
we would add the result of sampling \(\text{Laplace}(0,
\frac{25}{\epsilon})\) to the computed value. This preserves the
privacy of the student differing in \(D\) and \(D’\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-in-pharmacogenetics&#34;&gt;Privacy in Pharmacogenetics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matthew Fredrikson, Eric Lantz, Eric and Jha, Somesh and Lin, Simon and Page, David and Ristenpart, Thomas
&lt;em&gt;Privacy in Pharmacogenetics: An End-to-End Case Study of Personalized Warfarin Dosing&lt;/em&gt;. USENIX Security Symposium 2014. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/usenixsecurity14/sec14-paper-fredrikson-privacy.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their case study, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/usenixsecurity14/sec14-paper-fredrikson-privacy.pdf&#34;&gt;Fredrikson et al.&lt;/a&gt;
analyze personalized Warfarin doses, a widely used anticoagulant. Finding the correct dose of Warfarin is vitally important as both low and high doses may result in death of the patient &amp;ndash; literally, a matter of life and death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experiment was done on the available IWPC dataset which contains and uses demographic information &lt;em&gt;(age, height, weight, race)&lt;/em&gt;, genetic markers &lt;em&gt;(CYP2C9/VKORC1)&lt;/em&gt; and clinical histories of people around the world to predict their appropriate Warfarin dose. The IWPC has found that linear regression is the best learning model to fit the data and has made the model available for physicians&amp;rsquo; use in calculating the initial dose of the Warfarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s highlight how an adversary can use model inversion attack to violate the genomic privacy of a patient. We first initially assume that an adversary has black-box access to the trained model. As it turns out, due to the highly linear nature of the data, by running the model backwards, the sensitive genotype can be predicted given the stable dose of Warfarin, some basic demographic facts regarding the patient, and the marginal priors of the patient distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the attack work? First, the adversary computes all the values of the missing variables that could potentially agree with the given information. Then, the adversary runs the model forward for each hypothetical patient in the dataset to predict the stable Warfarin doses. Finally, the adversary performs a likelihood computation to find out which configuration of the missing variables are most probable. Given the information and model inversion setting, this algorithm is optimal, as it minimizes the adversaries misprediction rate. With respect to the baseline, the accuracy of the model inversion attack is only 5% lower in comparison to ideal prediction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/secML/secML.github.io/master/src/content/images/img2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Model inversion attack&#34; /&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/sites/default/files/conference/protected-files/sec14_slides_fredrikson.pdf&#34;&gt;Privacy in Pharmacogenetics presentation&lt;/a&gt; [2]
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As seen in this image, the attacker computes the values of missing variables, then predicts the Warfarin doses; and finally, using this information, finds the most likely configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding noise using differential privacy strategy can be a countermeasure against the model inversion attack. But using differential privacy decreases the utility of the trained model. Based on their simulated trials, authors claim that there is no such privacy budget that can prevent model inversion, without introducing  risk of overfixed dosing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/secML/secML.github.io/master/src/content/images/img3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Privacy budget plot&#34; /&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/sites/default/files/conference/protected-files/sec14_slides_fredrikson.pdf&#34;&gt;Privacy in Pharmacogenetics presentation&lt;/a&gt; [2]
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-netflix-prize-semi-supervised-deep-learning-from-private-training-data&#34;&gt;The Netflix Prize: Semi-supervised deep learning from private training data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank McSherry and Ilya Mironov, &lt;em&gt;Differentially Private Recommender Systems: Building Privacy into the Netflix Prize Contenders&lt;/em&gt;. KDD 2009. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/NetflixPrivacy.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional recommender systems are usually not designed with an emphasis on privacy, which can be detrimental when the adversary are able to create multiple accounts to affect the recommendation at will. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~shmat/shmat_oak08netflix.pdf&#34;&gt;Researchers&lt;/a&gt; have been successful in developing powerful attack linking records in the Netflix Prize data set with other public user data. The implication is that sensitive information as the input of a recommender system can be linked and made inference about. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~shmat/shmat_oak11ymal.pdf&#34;&gt;Similar practical examples&lt;/a&gt; include making inference about purchase history through Amazon’s recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McSherry and Mironov’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/NetflixPrivacy.pdf&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; adapted the leading recommendation algorithms (factor models and neighborhood models) to the differential privacy framework in order to develop a recommender system based on the Netflix data set while providing privacy guarantees. As mentioned in the above section, differential privacy enables privacy preserving computation by substantially precluding inference from the output data, unlike the prior efforts focusing mainly on cryptographic solutions that limit access to data of users. By doing so, it is conceivable that more uncertainty/noise is added to computation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One interesting aspect this paper dealt with is the privacy vs. accuracy tradeoff. Evaluation of their approach was applied to the Netflix Prize data set which bears extremely high dimensionality. The root mean squared error (RMSE) was used as the metric for accuracy. The findings are as the quality of privacy increases, the accuracy of the recommendation drops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/secML/secML.github.io/master/src/content/images/img4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;RMSE for four algorithms as a function of θ \\(\propto\\\) 1/σ on the Netflix Prize set.&#34; /&gt;
   &lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;(https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/NetflixPrivacy.pdf)&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Differentially Private Recommender Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [3]
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy vs. accuracy over time was also studied to explore how the loss of accuracy due to privacy-preserving decreased as more data become available for a fixed value of the privacy parameter. The results are summarized in the following figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/secML/secML.github.io/master/src/content/images/img5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Left scale—accuracy loss, right scale—the
number of records. The \\(x\\\)-axis is the number of days
elapsed since 7/1/2000.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;(https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/NetflixPrivacy.pdf)&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Differentially Private Recommender Systems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; [3]
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have introduced differential privacy and formally defined what is meant by preservation of \(\epsilon\)-differential privacy; discussed common solutions and how they fail; explained the properties of a differentially private algorithm, and how adding Laplace Noise enables \(\epsilon\)-differential private functions. We also discussed how in Membership Inference Attacks Against Machine Learning Models, Shokri et al. discuss attacking a black box model by training on a set of shadow models. Finally,  we discussed how in Privacy in Pharmacogenetics: An End-to-End Case Study of Personalized Warfarin Dosing Fredrikson et al. demonstrate how a model inversion attack can be employed to infer patient genotype information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Team Nematode: &lt;br /&gt;
Bargav Jayaraman, Guy &amp;ldquo;Jack&amp;rdquo; Verrier, Joshua Holtzman, Max Naylor, Nan Yang, Tanmoy Sen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~shmat/shmat_oak17.pdf&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; R. Shokri, M. Stronati, C. Song, V. Shmatikov, &amp;ldquo;Membership Inference Attacks Against Machine Learning Models.&amp;rdquo; May 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/usenixsecurity14/sec14-paper-fredrikson-privacy.pdf&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; M. Fredrikson, E. Lantz, S. Jha, S. Lin, D. Page, T. Ristenpart, &amp;ldquo;Privacy in Pharmacogenetics: An End-to-End Case Study of Personalized Warfarin Dosing.&amp;rdquo; August 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/NetflixPrivacy.pdf&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; F. McSherry, I. Mironov, &amp;ldquo;Differentially Private Recommender Systems: Building Privacy into the Netflix Prize Contenders.&amp;rdquo; June 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~shmat/shmat_oak08netflix.pdf&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; A. Narayanan, V. Shmatikov, &amp;ldquo;Robust De-anonymization of Large Sparse Datasets.&amp;rdquo; May 2008.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~shmat/shmat_oak11ymal.pdf&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; J. A. Calandrino, A. Kilzer, A. Narayanan, E. W. Felten, V. Shmatikov, &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;You Might Also Like&amp;rsquo;: Privacy Risks of Collaborative Filtering.&amp;rdquo; May 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lrdc.pitt.edu/schunn/cdi2009/presentations/Dwork.pdf&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; C. Dwork, &amp;ldquo;Differential Privacy and Pan-Private Algorithms.&amp;rdquo; August 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OfWj89oRD7g&#34;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; C. Dwork, &amp;ldquo;Differential Privacy - Lecture 1&amp;rdquo;. August 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 1: Intro to Adversarial Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/class1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/class1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;machine-learning-background&#34;&gt;Machine Learning Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- - Other ML algorithms use linear decision boundaries (SVM, LR, ...)
- Deep learning uses linear units with nonlinear composition
    - More susceptible to attacks
- Define terms like gradient and loss --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In supervised Machine Learning, we train models with training data
along with the label associated with it. We extract features from each
sample, and use an algorithm to train a model where the inputs are
those features and the output is the label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For classifying the testing data, the classifier uses decision
boundary to separate points of the data belonging to each class. In a
statistical-classification problem with two classes, a decision
boundary partitions all the underlying vector space into two separate
classes. A support vector machine (SVM) is a linear classifier which
constructs a boundary by focusing two closest points from different
classes and it finds the line that is equidistant to these two points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;loss-functions&#34;&gt;Loss Functions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A loss function define that how good a given model is at making
predictions for a given scenario. It has its own curve and its own
gradients. The slope of the curve indicates the appropriate way of
updating the parameters to make the model more accurate in case of
prediction. A frequently used loss function is the 0-1 loss function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/01_loss_function.png&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where \(I\) is the indicator notation. Hinge loss function is also popular in machine learning field. It provides a relatively tight, convex upper bound on the 0-1 indicator function.
s
&lt;!-- &lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/hinge_function.png&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;gradient-descent&#34;&gt;Gradient Descent&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gradient Descent is an optimization algorithm which is used to minimize cost function by iteratively moving the direction of the steepest descent. In machine learning, we use gradient descent to update the parameters (coefficients in Linear Regression and weight in neural networks) of our model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/gradient_descent_graph.png&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; &gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Image credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sebastianraschka.com/faq/docs/closed-form-vs-gd.html&#34;&gt;Sebastian Raschka&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the figure, weight is slowly decreasing from the initial stage. \(J_{min}\) is the minimum value of the cost function which can be obtained by optimizing the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, there have been many successful applications of Deep Neural
Networks (DNN) in the fields of information retrieval, computer
vision, and speech recognition. Despite their potential, deep neural
architectures, like all other machine learning approaches, are
vulnerable to what are known as adversarial samples. These systems can
be fooled by targeted manipulations which slightly modifying a real
example to trick the model into “believing” that this modified sample
belongs to an incorrect class with high confidence. To defend against
these adversarial attacks, many researchers are exploring several
directions including data augmentation, increasing model complexity,
retraining, pre-processing, etc. Their main goal is to protect the
model against adversarial manipulations by the attackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applications-and-vulnerabilities&#34;&gt;Applications and Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a better idea of what security and privacy mean in a machine learning context, we highlight a few
applications and examine the possible consequences of vulnerabilities in these domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most commonly-discussed applications is in self-driving
cars, which use machine learning algorithms for image recognition
tasks, such as identifying traffic signs and road hazards.  If an
attacker were to cause an erroneous classification, e.g. mistaking a
stop sign for a speed limit sign or missing a pedestrian in a
crosswalk, both property and human lives would be in
jeopardy. (Although luckily self-driving cars use a variety of other
techniques to avoid collisions, including detailed maps and LIDAR, so
are likely to not be directly vulnerable to image mis-classification
attacks.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine learning has also found a place in the medical world, being used to identify patterns and trends in patient histories that can be used for diagnoses, to recognize abnormalities in medical imaging, and even to evaluate the efficiency of a hospital&amp;rsquo;s workflow.  The use of machine learning in healthcare introduces a new concern - how can patient data be effectively utilized for beneficial purposes, like predicting appropriate drug dosages, without compromising patient privacy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are numerous other uses of ML today (targeted advertising, fraud detection, malware detection, etc.) and each carries particular security and privacy concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adversarial-examples&#34;&gt;Adversarial Examples&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In machine learning, an adversarial example is an input that has been manipulated so that the model returns a different, incorrect output.  A classic adversarial example for image classification is from a paper by &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1412.6572.pdf&#34;&gt;Goodfellow et al.&lt;/a&gt;, which features a photo of a panda that was originally classified correctly, but is misclassified when carefully-crafted noise is added.  The model classifies the new image as a gibbon, even though human eyes can easily see it is a panda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/panda.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; &gt;
&lt;br&gt; Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1412.6572.pdf&#34;&gt;Goodfellow Paper&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As outlined in &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1712.03141.pdf&#34;&gt;Biggio et al.&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; paper on the history of adversarial machine learning, adversarial examples were first described in 2004 in the context of email spam filters. At this time, &lt;a href=&#34;https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~pedrod/papers/kdd04.pdf&#34;&gt;Dalvi et al.&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ix.cs.uoregon.edu/~lowd/kdd05lowd.pdf&#34;&gt;Lowd and Meek&lt;/a&gt; realized that slight modifications to spam emails allowed them to pass through the filters, without greatly affecting the content of the message. From this point, the field expanded to study the potential for adversarial examples in other realms, like machine-learning-based image and malware classification.  The increased usage of deep learning techniques for object recognition led to a surge in interest around 2014, when Szegedy et al. showed that deep convolutional neural networks were also susceptible to adversarial examples.  Since then, interest in this field has only continued to increase, with more and more papers published each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;classifying-attacks&#34;&gt;Classifying Attacks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attacks can be categorized by many different characteristics, but are often referred to in terms of the attack method, the goal of the attack, and the adversary&amp;rsquo;s level of knowledge, as detailed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1611.03814.pdf&#34;&gt;Papernot et al.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;attack-method&#34;&gt;Attack Method&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A poisoning attack is when the adversary adds carefully-crafted samples into the training data, thereby disrupting the learning process and manipulating the final trained model.  An evasion attack occurs when a sample originally correctly classified into class A is manipulated and fed back into the model, now receiving an output that is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; class A.  A key difference between these two attacks is where each occurs in the ML pipeline: poisoning attacks occur before the training stage and evasion attacks occuring after training, during the testing stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/ml_pipeline.jpg&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; &gt;
&lt;br&gt; Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1dFRjRfCIz1TChZYfIY_FLYiSk7nNmdBY2luJ8T_TCAE/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Presentation Slides&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;goal-of-attack&#34;&gt;Goal of Attack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the adversary is another way to categorize attacks, which
in this case means whether or not there was a specific goal
classification or not.  &lt;em&gt;Error-generic&lt;/em&gt; (also called &lt;em&gt;untargeted&lt;/em&gt;)
attacks aim to find a sample close to a given seed that is
misclassified, but do not have a specific target output
class. &lt;em&gt;Error-specific&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;targeted&lt;/em&gt;) attacks deliberately change the
seed sample&amp;rsquo;s classification from the original class A to a chosen
class B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;adversary-knowledge&#34;&gt;Adversary Knowledge&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The level of knowledge the adversary possesses generally falls into one of three loosely defined categories: black box, grey box, and white box attacks.  Black box attacks assume the lowest level of adversary knowledge, generally only allowing the final classification to be known without any finer details about the model.  On the other end of the spectrum, white box attacks assume that the attacker knows everything about the model, including the specific algorithm used, the feature set, the training data, etc. An attack by an adversary who knows more about the model than a black box but less than a white box is called a grey box attack, although the exact definition tends to vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/boxes.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-machine-learning-as-a-potemkin-village&#34;&gt;Modern Machine Learning as a Potemkin village&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/potemkin.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Potemkin village&amp;rdquo; describes a difference between appeance and reality. In a &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1412.6572&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; by Goodfellow, Shlens, and Szegdy, modern machine learning methods are described as building &amp;ldquo;a Potemkin village that works well on naturally occuring data, but is exposed as a fake when one visits points in space that do not have high probability in the data distribution.&amp;rdquo; The apparent fragility of deep neural networks has been particuarly exposed, as seen in the panda picture above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two-faced nature of machine learning models to be both fragile and robout from two different angles leads to concerns in the security of machine learning algorithms. High confidence in classifying adversarial examples poses a threat to the integrity of the model&amp;rsquo;s output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;fast-gradient-sign-method-fgsm&#34;&gt;Fast gradient sign method (FGSM)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1412.6572&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; mentioned a method for generating adversarial examples. Fast gradient sign method maximizes the error between the ground truth classification of the sample and minimizes the error to the target classification. The method is effecitve is generating the best pixels to change to achieve a higher loss, essentially acting as a reverse optimization method. FGSM simply traverses the loss curve by moving in the opposite direction of the gradient loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/formula.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we discussed, the sign method in the FGSM is an approximation to the actual gradient. Although the most accurate method would use the true gradient, the sign of the gradient is taken for the sake efficiency: since \(\epsilon\) reflect the adversarial strength (the maximum size perturbation allowed), this represents taking the largest step possible in each dimension in the direction given by the gradient. (There are many variations on FGSM that we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss in later posts, including iterative versions where a sequence of smaller steps is used.) FGSM showcases the fragility of machine learning models especially through visualizations such as the panda example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adversarial-training&#34;&gt;Adversarial training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;effects-of-nonlinearities&#34;&gt;Effects of nonlinearities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One criticism of deep neural networks is that their nonlinearity creates vulnerabilities that can be exploited by adversarial examples.  As shown below, the mode function cuts through the data points linearly, while the function drawn by the neural network conforms more tightly to the training data points.  This overfitting to training data creates pockets in which the class chosen by the function does not match the ground truth class value for a given data point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://secml.github.io/images/capacity.png&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; &gt;
&lt;br&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.papernot.fr/files/16-mcdaniel-sp-machine-learning-in-adversarial-settings.pdf&#34;&gt;McDaniel, Papernot, and Celik, &lt;em&gt;IEEE Security &amp;amp; Privacy Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a possible solution, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1312.6199.pdf&#34;&gt;Szegedy et al.&lt;/a&gt; proposed incorporating adversarial examples into the training data.  Using various techniques to find the vulnerable pockets in the model, the authors were able to generate examples that would fall into those adversarial region.  Adding those samples to the training data results in a new model that does not follow the original training points as closely, creating a smoother, more accurate function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using an adversarial &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regularization_(mathematics)&#34;&gt;regularizer&lt;/a&gt; is also a technique to limit overfitting and vulnerability to adversarial examples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1412.6572&#34;&gt;Goodfellow et al.&lt;/a&gt; describes a technique using the fast gradient sign method mentioned above as a regularizer. Their method generates adversarial examples using the fast gradient sign method and then trains the model with the adversarial examples. By continually updating the adversarial examples to the model, the adversarial regions are minimized. In the paper, they were able to reduce the error rate on adversarial examples from 0.94% to 0.84% using this approach. In order to reduce this error further, they also increased the model size and introduced early stopping on adversarial validation set error. Using these additional techniques they were able to drop the error rate on adversarial examples based on the FGSM from 89.4% to 17.9%. A combination of techniques introduced in training can significantly decrease the vunerability to simple adversarial attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transferability-of-adversarial-samples&#34;&gt;Transferability of adversarial samples&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As shown above, an adversarial sample can fool a machine-learned model to misclassify it with high confidence. In particular, the adversarial samples made to fool image classifiers show how an adversarial sample can be indistinguishable to humans from legitimate samples. Additionally, examples that evade one classifier tend to evade others. This poses a vulnerability for machine learned models, one that can be exploited with cross-evasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;learning-classifier-substitutes&#34;&gt;Learning classifier substitutes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1605.07277&#34;&gt;Papernot et al.&lt;/a&gt;, took advantage of the transferability of adversarial examples on a remote DNN by training a new model with their own synthetic data. By using a relatively small number of queries to label their data, they trained a substitute model which they then used to craft adversarial samples. Demonstrating transferability, 84.24% of the adversarial samples trained from the substitute model fooled the remote DNN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To explicitly demonstrate the phenomenon of both intra and cross-technique transferability, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1605.07277&#34;&gt;Papernot et al.&lt;/a&gt; used five different machine learning algorithms on five disjoint training sets of MNIST dataset. With this setup, adversarial samples trained from one technique on one subset of the training data fools &amp;ndash; to varying degrees &amp;ndash; models trained by a different subset of the training data as well as a different technique. Furthermore, an ensemble classifier could be fooled at a rate of up to 44%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Team Panda:&lt;br /&gt;
Christopher Geier,
Faysal Hossain Shezan,
Helen Simecek,
Lawrence Hook,
Nishant Jha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1412.6572.pdf&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; I.J. Goodfellow, J. Shlens, C. Szegedy, &amp;ldquo;Explaining
and Harnessing Adversarial Examples.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;ArXiv e-prints&lt;/em&gt;, December 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1712.03141.pdf&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; B. Biggio, F. Roli, &amp;ldquo;Wild patterns: Ten years after the rise of
adversarial machine learning.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;arXiv preprint arXiv:1712.03141&lt;/em&gt;, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~pedrod/papers/kdd04.pdf&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; N. Dalvi, P. Domingos, Mausam, S. Sanghai, D. Verma, &amp;ldquo;Adversarial classification,&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Int’l Conf. Knowl. Disc. and Data Mining&lt;/em&gt;, 2004, pp. 99–108.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ix.cs.uoregon.edu/~lowd/kdd05lowd.pdf&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; D. Lowd, C. Meek, &amp;ldquo;Adversarial learning,&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Int’l Conf. Knowl. Disc. and Data Mining&lt;/em&gt;, ACM Press, Chicago, IL, USA, 2005, pp. 641–647.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1611.03814.pdf&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; N. Papernot, P. McDaniel, A. Sinha, M. Wellman, &amp;ldquo;Towards the science of security and privacy in machine learning.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;IEEE European Symposium on Security and Privacy&lt;/em&gt;,
2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1605.07277&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; N. Papernot, P. Mcdaniel, I.J. Goodfellow, &amp;ldquo;Transferability in machine learning: from phenomena to black-box attacks using adversarial samples&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;arXiv preprint arXiv:1605.07277&lt;/em&gt;, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1312.6199.pdf&#34;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; C. Szegedy, W. Zaremba, I. Sutskever, J Bruna, D. Erhan, I.J. Goodfellow, R. Fergus. &amp;ldquo;Intriguing properties of neural networks.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;ICLR,&lt;/em&gt; abs/1312.6199, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Week</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/first-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/first-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This message was also sent out by email.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since not everyone has joined the slack yet, I&amp;rsquo;m sending this out by
email, but please make sure to join
&lt;a href=&#34;https://secprivml.slack.com&#34;&gt;https://secprivml.slack.com&lt;/a&gt; soon. I
will use that for future communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have grouped the 18 full participants in the class into three teams of six:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Bus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anant Kharkar&lt;br /&gt;
Ashley Gao&lt;br /&gt;
Atallah Hezbor&lt;br /&gt;
Joshua Holtzman&lt;br /&gt;
Mainuddin Ahmad Jonas&lt;br /&gt;
Weilin Xu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Gibbon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aditi Narvekar&lt;br /&gt;
Austin Chen&lt;br /&gt;
Ethan Lowman&lt;br /&gt;
Guy &amp;ldquo;Jack&amp;rdquo; Verrier&lt;br /&gt;
Jialei Fu&lt;br /&gt;
Jin Ding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Panda:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bargav Jayaraman&lt;br /&gt;
Christopher Geier&lt;br /&gt;
Faysal Hossain Shezan&lt;br /&gt;
Nathaniel Grevatt&lt;br /&gt;
Nishant Jha&lt;br /&gt;
Tanmoy Sen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teams will probably adjust a bit over the next week as some people
who registered for the class didn&amp;rsquo;t submit a survey, and others may be
joining the class late, etc., but otherwise we will plan to keep with
these teams through spring break and possible re-arrange things after
that.  You can, of course, rename your team and develop your own
adversarial (but tasteful) team icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week, one team will be responsible for leading the class, one
team for blogging (writing a summary of the class), and one team for
food. Everyone in the class is expected to do the preparation for each
meeting, which will usually involve reading a few papers (but may
involve other activities, at the design of the leading team).  See
&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/teams/&#34;&gt;https://secml.github.io/teams/&lt;/a&gt; for
the description of team responsibilities.  For the first week, Team
Bus will be the leading team, Team Gibbon will be the feeding team,
and Team Panda will be the blogging team.  I have created a slack
channel for each team, and you should have an invitation to join
it. The immediate tasks for each team are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Team Bus: decide on a leader who will be responsible for coordinating your team for this week, come up with some ideas what you would like to do for Friday&amp;rsquo;s meeting, make sure there are some people who can come to my office hours on Monday (2:30pm) - if not enough people can come then, arrange an alternative time with me, and plan an exciting and worthwhile seminar for Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Team Gibbon: you are the feeding team for this week, so should select 2-3 people to take care of this. One of you should pick up a credit card from me on Thursday to pay for the food. You will be leading the seminar on 2 Feb, so should determine a leader for this, and once Team Bus posts the topic and paper for this week (which should happen on Monday), should start planning your topic. We should meet briefly after Friday&amp;rsquo;s seminar, to discuss your plans, and then a longer meeting the following Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Team Panda: you are the blogging team for this week, so should get familiar with &lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/blogging/&#34;&gt;https://secml.github.io/blogging/&lt;/a&gt;. You will be leading the seminar or 9 Feb, so should start thinking of topics you would like to lead. You should identify leaders for blogging, feeding, and leading to be ready for the next 3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dave&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Seminar</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/starting-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/starting-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our first seminar meeting will be Friday, January 26 (not this Friday, which would normally be the first class day, since I will be getting back from California too late to meet this week). Meetings will be Fridays in Rice 032, 9:30am-noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;rsquo;re missing the normal first meeting, I want to do as much of the organizational stuff this week to be able to have a substantive first meeting next week. This means we will group students into teams, have a team assigned to lead the first class, and announced topic and readings by next Tuesday (Jan 23).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable this, everyone interested in participating in the class in any way should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Submit this form by Wednesday (Jan 24): &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/forms/FqSmUNHYBPbaKsg72&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/forms/FqSmUNHYBPbaKsg72&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/syllabus/&#34;&gt;course syllabus&lt;/a&gt;, and follow the directions there to join the seminar slack group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will work out the teams based on the form submissions, and set up the schedule for leading classes/blogging. I will have office hours on Monday (Jan 22) at 2:30pm. People from the first presenting team will be expect to meet with me then (not necessarily everyone but at least some of the team), and anyone with questions about the seminar is also welcome to come by. (If this time works for the class, we&amp;rsquo;ll keep this as my regular office hours time for the semester.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry for missing the first class, but I think we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to manage most of what we would have done the first day electronically, and be able to have an effective first meeting on Jan 26.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus Posted</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/syllabusposted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/syllabusposted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/a&gt; is now posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This graduate-level special topics course will be offered in Spring
2018. Meetings will be &lt;strong&gt;Fridays, 9:30-noon&lt;/strong&gt; in Rice Hall 032. More
information will be posted here soon, but the seminar format will be
roughly similar to what we used to &lt;a
href=&#34;https://tlseminar.github.io&#34;&gt;TLSeminar&lt;/a&gt; last Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seminar will focus on understanding the risks adversaries pose to
machine learning systems, and how to design more robust machine
learning systems to mitigate those risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seminar is open to ambitious undergraduate students (with
instructor permission), and to graduate students interested in
research in adversarial machine learning, privacy-preserving machine
learning, fairness and transparency in machine learning, and other
related topics.  Previous background in machine learning and security
is beneficial, but not required so long as you are willing and able to
learn some foundational materials on your own.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; For more
information, contact &lt;A href=&#34;https://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans&#34;&gt;David
Evans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;resources-for-adversarial-machine-learning-research&#34;&gt;Resources for Adversarial Machine Learning Research&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;adversarial-machine-learning-toolkits&#34;&gt;Adversarial Machine Learning Toolkits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;evademl.org/zoo&#34;&gt;EvadeML-Zoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tensorflow/cleverhans&#34;&gt;cleverhans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;machine-learning-systems&#34;&gt;Machine Learning Systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebookresearch/Detectron&#34;&gt;Detectron&lt;/a&gt; - Facebook&amp;rsquo;s research platform for object detection research (including RetinaNet)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/teams&#34;&gt;Teams&lt;/a&gt; for the class teams and responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; width=&#34;20%&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Date&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td width=&#34;30%&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Topic&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; width=&#34;10%&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bus&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; width=&#34;10%&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gibbon&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; width=10%&gt;&lt;b&gt;Panda&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; width=12%&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;-1&#34;&gt;Nematode&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class1&#34;&gt;Class 1&lt;/a&gt; (26 Jan)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Intro to Adversarial ML&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class2&#34;&gt;Class 2&lt;/a&gt; (2 Feb)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Privacy and ML&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class3&#34;&gt;Class 3&lt;/a&gt; (9 Feb)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Adversarial Examples&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class4&#34;&gt;Class 4&lt;/a&gt; (16 Feb)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Privacy in Action&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class5&#34;&gt;Class 5&lt;/a&gt; (23 Feb)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class6&#34;&gt;Class 6&lt;/a&gt; (2 Mar)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=6 bgcolor=&#34;#66EEAA&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Spring Break&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class7&#34;&gt;Class 7&lt;/a&gt; (16 Mar)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class8&#34;&gt;Class 8&lt;/a&gt; (23 Mar)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class9&#34;&gt;Class 9&lt;/a&gt; (30 Mar)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class10&#34;&gt;Class 10&lt;/a&gt; (6 Apr)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class11&#34;&gt;Class 11&lt;/a&gt; (13 Apr)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class12&#34;&gt;Class 12&lt;/a&gt; (20 Apr)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34; &gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#DEF&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  bgcolor=&#34;#CCDD55&#34;&gt;Lead&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/class13&#34;&gt;Class 13&lt;/a&gt; (26 Apr)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;  colspan=5 bgcolor=&#34;#FF3&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Mini-Conference&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cs6501-security-and-privacy-of-machine-learning&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cs6501: Security and Privacy of Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of Virginia, Spring 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meetings:&lt;/strong&gt; Fridays, 9:30AM - noon, Rice Hall 032&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Objective.&lt;/strong&gt; This seminar will focus on understanding the
  risks adversaries pose to machine learning systems, and how to
  design more robust machine learning systems to mitigate those risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expected Background:&lt;/strong&gt; Previous background in machine learning and
security is beneficial, but not required so long as you are willing
and able to learn some foundational materials on your own. Most
students in the seminar should have either strong background in
machine learning, or strong background in security and privacy, but it
is not expected that most students have extensive background in both
areas. The seminar is open to ambitious undergraduate students (with
instructor permission), and to graduate students interested in
research in adversarial machine learning, privacy-preserving machine
learning, fairness and transparency in machine learning, and other
related topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coordinator:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans&#34;&gt;David Evans&lt;/a&gt;
  (evans@virginia.edu). My
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans/office&#34;&gt;office&lt;/a&gt; is Rice 507.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-expectations&#34;&gt;Course Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students in the seminar are expected to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lead discussions on interesting topics during the class meetings.
For each week, there will be a team of students charged with
preparing a topic and leading the discussion, and another team
charged with writing a blog post about the class. Students
responsible for posting the blog summary will be different from the
ones charged with leading the topic discussion, but should work
closely with the leaders on the posted write-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Particpate actively in class meetings.  This means being prepared to
contribute by doing the assigned preparation (which will typically
involve reading a few research papers, but may involve other things
also) and thinking about the materials deeply to be able to
contribute well to discussions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contribute fully to a team that develops a course-long project which
could either be a research project or a systematization of knowledge
project. We will discuss this more in an early class, and form teams
based on interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;communications&#34;&gt;Communications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Website:&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://secml.github.io/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  All
  course materials will be posted on the course website, and students
  will be expected to provide materials to add to this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slack:&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://secprivml.slack.com&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://secprivml.slack.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  We
  will use a slack group for class communications.  You can join using
  any &lt;code&gt;@virginia.edu&lt;/code&gt; email address.  You can also create slack
  channels for your team communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;honor-and-responsibility&#34;&gt;Honor and Responsibility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe strongly in the value of a &lt;em&gt;community of trust&lt;/em&gt;, and expect
all of the students in this class to contribute to strenghtening and
enhancing that community.  The course will be better for everyone if
everyone can assume everyone else is trustworthy. The course staff
starts with the assumption that all students at the university deserve
to be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this course, we will be learning about and exploring some
vulnerabilities that could be used to compromise deployed systems.
&lt;strong&gt;You are trusted to behave responsibility and ethically.&lt;/strong&gt; You may
not attack any system without permission of its owners, and may not
use anything you learn in this class for evil.  If you have any doubts
about whether or not something you want to do is ethical and legal,
you should check with the course instructor before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;area-requirements&#34;&gt;Area Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note for CS Graduate Students.&lt;/strong&gt; This course is mislisted in SIS
(indeed, it is a &amp;ldquo;bug&amp;rdquo; in the setup of SIS that cannot be overcome
that requires all grad courses to be assigned areas) as counting for
the &amp;ldquo;Software Systems&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Theory&amp;rdquo; area requirements.  As per the
actual rules in the Graduate Handbook, a cs6501 seminar course does
not a priori count for any particular areas.  It may be possible to
count it for any area, but it would be up to you to make the case to
your committee that it should count for a given area. In most cases,
this will depend a lot on what you individually do in the class - for
example, you could select presentation topics and a topic for you
project that would make a strong case for counting it for the &amp;ldquo;Theory&amp;rdquo;
area, but someone else who does a systems-focused project would be
able to count it for a different area. I can help provide guidance on
this, but it is ultimately up to your committee to decide if a course
counts for a particular area requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/teams/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;teams&#34;&gt;Teams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr bgcolor=&#34;#CCC&#34;&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Team Bus&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Team Gibbon&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Team Panda&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Team Nematode&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Anant Kharkar&lt;br&gt;
Atallah Hezbor  &lt;br&gt;
Bhuvanesh Murali&lt;br&gt;
Mainuddin Jonas&lt;br&gt;  
Weilin Xu&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Aditi Narvekar&lt;br&gt;  
Austin Chen  &lt;br&gt;
Ethan Lowman  &lt;br&gt;
Jin Ding  &lt;br&gt;
Suya
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Christopher Geier  &lt;br&gt;
Faysal Hossain Shezan  &lt;br&gt;
Helen Simecek&lt;br&gt;
Lawrence Hook&lt;br&gt;
Nishant Jha  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Bargav Jayaraman&lt;br&gt;  
Guy &#34;Jack&#34; Verrier&lt;br&gt;  
Joshua Holtzman  &lt;br&gt;
Max Naylor&lt;br&gt;
Nan Yang&lt;br&gt;
Tanmoy Sen  
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;responsibilities&#34;&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each week (except for project proposal and presentation weeks),
one team will be responsible for Leading the class, one team for
writing a Blog post on the class topic, and one team for arranging
food.  See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/schedule&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/a&gt; for team responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leading Team.&lt;/strong&gt;  The team responsible for leading a class should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two weeks before the scheduled class, meet briefly with me (Dave) to
discuss plan for the class. You should decide on a team leader for
this class, who will be the one responsible for making sure everyone
on the team knows what they are doing and coordinating the team&amp;rsquo;s
efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Monday the week of the class, at least a few representatives
from the team should come to my office hours to discuss the plan for
the class.  You should come prepared to this meeting with suggested
papers and ideas about how to present them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No later than the Monday before class, send out to the class Slack group the preparation materials for the class.  This can include links to papers to read, but could also include exercises to do or software to install and experiment with, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day of class: lead an interesting, engaging, and illuminating class! This is a 2.5 hour class, so it can&amp;rsquo;t just be a series of unconnected, dull presentations. You need to think of things to do in class to make it more worthwhile and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After class: help the Blogging team by providing them with your materials, answering their questions, and reviewing their write-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blogging Team.&lt;/strong&gt; The team responsible for blogging a class should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The week before the scheduled class, develop a team plan for how to
manage the blogging. One team member should be designated the team
leader for the blogging, and post on slack so we know who is
responsible. The blogging leader is responsible for making sure the
team is well coordinated and everyone knows what they are doing and
follows through on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;During class, participate actively in the class, and take detailed
notes (this can be distributed among the team).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the Tuesday following class, have a draft of the blog post ready,
and share it with the rest of the class (including the leading team
and coordinators) for comments. Details on how to prepare the blog post are on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/blogging&#34;&gt;Blogging Mechanics&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the next Friday (one week after the class), have a final version
of the blog post ready to add to the course site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feeding Team.&lt;/strong&gt; The team responsible for food should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plan among yourselves what food to bring and who is responsible.  If
you want to use my credit card to buy food, borrow it. You can stop
by Thursday afternoon to pick it up from me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bring something yummy and something with caffiene, but not too messy
or disruptive, to class. A simple choice is to get a coffee
container and bagels from the bagel shop in Rice Hall (but make sure
to get the order in early enough to be ready before class). More
adventurous choices are encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure to clean up the room at the end of class. If we get caught
leaving a mess, we probably will not be allowed to have food
anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save the receipts to get reimbursed, and take care of the
reimbursement. This is easiest if you just borrow my credit card and
then all you need to do is send me an image of the receipt (or hand
me a physical receipt).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some suggestions for how to create the class blog posts for
your assigned classes.  I believe each team has at least a few members
with enough experience using git and web contruction tools that
following these instructions won&amp;rsquo;t be a big burden, but if you have
other ways you want to build your blog page for a topic let me know
and we can discuss alternative options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.  Hugo is a static website
generator that builds a site from Markdown pages.  (With homebrew on
Mac OS X, this is easy: &lt;code&gt;brew update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew install hugo&lt;/code&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clone the github repository,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/secML/secML.github.io&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://github.com/secML/secML.github.io&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
This is what is used to build the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://secml.github.io/&#34;&gt;https://secml.github.io/&lt;/a&gt; site.  If you are
working with multiple teammates on the blog post (which you probably
should be), you can add write permissions for everyone to the cloned
repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should create your page in the &lt;code&gt;web/content/post/&lt;/code&gt;
subdirectory. You can start by copying an earlier file in that
directory (e.g., &lt;code&gt;class1.md&lt;/code&gt;) and updating the header section
(between the &lt;code&gt;+++&lt;/code&gt; marks) and replacing everything after that with
your content.  Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to &lt;strong&gt;update the date&lt;/strong&gt; so your page will
appear in the right order. You can put &lt;code&gt;draft = true&lt;/code&gt; in the header,
so your page will not appear on the course website until it is
ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use multiple files (but probably only one in
the &lt;code&gt;post/&lt;/code&gt; directory (this will show up as pages on the front
list).  Use the &lt;code&gt;web/content/images&lt;/code&gt; directory for images and the
&lt;code&gt;web/content/docs&lt;/code&gt; directory for papers.  Using images and other
resources to make your post interesting and visually compelling is
highly encouraged!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write the blog page using Markdown.  Markdown is a simple markup
language that can be used to easily generate both HTML and other
output document formats.  You can probably figure out everything you
need by looking at previous posts, but for a summary of Markdown,
see &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax&#34;&gt;Markdown: Syntax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can incorporate latex math into your markdown. Use &lt;code&gt;\\(&lt;/code&gt; inline &lt;code&gt;\\)&lt;/code&gt; for inline math, e.g., &lt;code&gt;\\( J_{min}\\}&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$$ ... $$&lt;/code&gt; for display math.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your post should include credits for any external material you use,
especially for any images you incorporate that you didn&amp;rsquo;t produce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please include full references to the papers, and links to the most
definitive source available (usually this is to arxiv or a
conference site, but could be the author&amp;rsquo;s page). You should include
additional links to relevant and useful reference or code
repositories. Its good to have an overview section at the beginning
of the post with links to all the main papers covered, and then to
have links in specific sections to what is being covered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To test the post, run &lt;code&gt;make develop&lt;/code&gt; (in the &lt;code&gt;web/&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory of
your repository).  This starts the Hugo development server, usually
on port 1313 (unless that port is already in use).  Then, you can
view the site with a browser at &lt;code&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you are ready, submit a pull request to incorporate your
changes into the main repository (and public course website).  Also,
send a message to me (dave) on slack, so I know the post is ready to
review.  At this stage, I will probably make some requests for
improvements, and then will post the edited version to the course
site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>