<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>secML</title>
    <link>https://secml.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on secML</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://secml.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 1: Intro to Adversarial Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/class1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/class1/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Background In supervised Machine Learning, we train models with training data along with the label associated with it. We extract features from each sample, and use an algorithm to train a model where the inputs are those features and the output is the label.
For classifying the testing data, the classifier uses decision boundary to separate points of the data belonging to each class. In a statistical-classification problem with two classes, a decision boundary partitions all the underlying vector space into two separate classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Week</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/first-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/first-week/</guid>
      <description>This message was also sent out by email.
Since not everyone has joined the slack yet, I&amp;rsquo;m sending this out by email, but please make sure to join https://secprivml.slack.com soon. I will use that for future communications.
I have grouped the 18 full participants in the class into three teams of six:
Team Bus:
Anant Kharkar
Ashley Gao
Atallah Hezbor
Joshua Holtzman
Mainuddin Ahmad Jonas
Weilin Xu
Team Gibbon:
Aditi Narvekar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Seminar</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/starting-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/starting-seminar/</guid>
      <description>Our first seminar meeting will be Friday, January 26 (not this Friday, which would normally be the first class day, since I will be getting back from California too late to meet this week). Meetings will be Fridays in Rice 032, 9:30am-noon.
Since we&amp;rsquo;re missing the normal first meeting, I want to do as much of the organizational stuff this week to be able to have a substantive first meeting next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus Posted</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/syllabusposted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/syllabusposted/</guid>
      <description>The Syllabus is now posted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>This graduate-level special topics course will be offered in Spring 2018. Meetings will be Fridays, 9:30-noon in Rice Hall 032. More information will be posted here soon, but the seminar format will be roughly similar to what we used to TLSeminar last Spring.
This seminar will focus on understanding the risks adversaries pose to machine learning systems, and how to design more robust machine learning systems to mitigate those risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>Resources for Adversarial Machine Learning Research Adversarial Machine Learning Toolkits EvadeML-Zoo
cleverhans
Machine Learning Systems Detectron - Facebook&amp;rsquo;s research platform for object detection research (including RetinaNet)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>See Teams for the class teams and responsibilities.
 DateTopicBusGibbonPandaNematode Class 1 (26 Jan)Intro to Adversarial MLLeadFoodBlog Class 2 (2 Feb)Privacy and MLLeadFoodBlog Class 3 (9 Feb)Adversarial Examples and DefensesBlogLeadFood Class 4 (16 Feb)FoodBlogLead Class 5 (23 Feb)LeadFoodBlog Class 6 (2 Mar)BlogLeadFood Spring Break Class 7 (16 Mar)BlogLeadFood Class 8 (23 Mar)FoodBlogLead Class 9 (30 Mar)LeadFoodBlog Class 10 (6 Apr)BlogLeadFood Class 11 (13 Apr)BlogLeadFood Class 12 (20 Apr)FoodBlogLead Class 13 (26 Apr)Mini-Conference  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Syllabus cs6501: Security and Privacy of Machine Learning University of Virginia, Spring 2018
Meetings: Fridays, 9:30AM - noon, Rice Hall 032
Course Objective. This seminar will focus on understanding the risks adversaries pose to machine learning systems, and how to design more robust machine learning systems to mitigate those risks.
Expected Background: Previous background in machine learning and security is beneficial, but not required so long as you are willing and able to learn some foundational materials on your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/teams/</guid>
      <description>Teams  Team BusTeam GibbonTeam PandaTeam Nematode   Anant Kharkar
Atallah Hezbor Bhuvanesh Murali
Mainuddin Jonas
Weilin Xu
  Aditi Narvekar
Austin Chen Ethan Lowman Jialei Fu Jin Ding Suya   Christopher Geier Faysal Hossain Shezan Helen Simecek
Lawrence Hook
Nishant Jha   Bargav Jayaraman
Guy &#34;Jack&#34; Verrier
Joshua Holtzman Max Naylor
Nan Yang
Tanmoy Sen   
Responsibilities For each week (except for project proposal and presentation weeks), one team will be responsible for Leading the class, one team for writing a Blog post on the class topic, and one team for arranging food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://secml.github.io/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secml.github.io/blogging/</guid>
      <description>Here are some suggestions for how to create the class blog posts for your assigned classes. I believe each team has at least a few members with enough experience using git and web contruction tools that following these instructions won&amp;rsquo;t be a big burden, but if you have other ways you want to build your blog page for a topic let me know and we can discuss alternative options.
 Install Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>